<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-07-10T12:59:43+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">Lutfi Ayu Art</title><subtitle>There is no abstract art. You must always start with something afterward you can remove all traces of reality - Pablo Picasso
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Abstract Act History</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/07/07/abstracthistory.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Abstract Act History " /><published>2017-07-07T17:23:08+07:00</published><updated>2017-07-07T17:23:08+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/07/07/abstracthistory</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/07/07/abstracthistory.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/b/bb/First_abstract_watercolor_kandinsky_1910.jpg/300px-First_abstract_watercolor_kandinsky_1910.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;...&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Abstract art&lt;/code&gt; uses a visual language of shape, form, color and line to create a composition which may exist with a degree of independence from visual references in the world. Western art had been, from the Renaissance up to the middle of the 19th century, underpinned by the logic of perspective and an attempt to reproduce an illusion of visible reality. The arts of cultures other than the European had become accessible and showed alternative ways of describing visual experience to the artist. By the end of the 19th century many artists felt a need to create a new kind of art which would encompass the fundamental changes taking place in technology, science and philosophy. The sources from which individual artists drew their theoretical arguments were diverse, and reflected the social and intellectual preoccupations in all areas of Western culture at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;art&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;non&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;figurative&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;art&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;non&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;objective&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;art&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nonrepresentational&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;loosely&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;related&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;terms&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;They&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;similar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;perhaps&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;identical&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;meaning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstraction indicates a departure from reality in depiction of imagery in art. This departure from accurate representation can be slight, partial, or complete. Abstraction exists along a continuum. Even art that aims for verisimilitude of the highest degree can be said to be abstract, at least theoretically, since perfect representation is likely to be exceedingly elusive. Artwork which takes liberties, altering for instance color and form in ways that are conspicuous, can be said to be partially abstract. Total abstraction bears no trace of any reference to anything recognizable. In geometric abstraction, for instance, one is unlikely to find references to naturalistic entities. Figurative art and total abstraction are almost mutually exclusive. But figurative and representational (or realistic) art often contains partial abstraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both geometric abstraction and lyrical abstraction are often totally abstract. Among the very numerous art movements that embody partial abstraction would be for instance fauvism in which color is conspicuously and deliberately altered vis-a-vis reality, and cubism, which blatantly alters the forms of the real life entities depicted.
Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstract_art&quot;&gt;Abstract Art&lt;/a&gt; for more info on about abstract art history.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">London Abstract Exhibition 2017</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/07/07/abstractartexhibition.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="London Abstract Exhibition 2017" /><published>2017-07-07T17:23:08+07:00</published><updated>2017-07-07T17:23:08+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/07/07/abstractartexhibition</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/07/07/abstractartexhibition.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date : 24 September 2016 — 2 January 2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day : Saturday – Thursday 10am – 6pm , Friday 10am – 10pm.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Place : Main Galleries, Burlington House&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Admission :£17 (£19 with donation) Concessions available.&lt;/strong&gt; Friends of the RA and under 16s go free. Tickets include a multimedia guide and both Friends of the RA and their family guest will receive one for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exhibition Description :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the “age of anxiety” surrounding the Second World War and the years of free jazz and Beat poetry, artists like Pollock, Rothko and de Kooning broke from accepted conventions to unleash a new confidence in painting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often monumental in scale, their works are at times intense, spontaneous and deeply expressive. At others they are more contemplative, presenting large fields of colour that border on the sublime. These radical creations redefined the nature of painting, and were intended not simply to be admired from a distance but as two-way encounters between artist and viewer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a watershed moment in the evolution of 20th-century art, yet, remarkably, there has been no major survey of the movement since 1959.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This autumn we bring together some of the most celebrated art of the past century, offering the chance to experience the powerful collective impact of Pollock, Rothko, Still, de Kooning, Newman, Kline, Smith, Guston and Gorky as their works dominate our galleries with their scale and vitality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also acknowledge the lesser-known figures who contributed to the development of the movement. Finally, we include photography and sculpture to complete an ambitious re-evaluation of the phenomenon that saw New York take over from Paris as the capital of the art world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is curated by the independent art historian Dr David Anfam, alongside Edith Devaney, Contemporary Curator at the Royal Academy of Arts. Dr Anfam is the preeminent authority on Abstract Expressionism, the author of the catalogue raisonné of Mark Rothko’s paintings and Senior Consulting Curator at the Clyfford Still Museum, Denver.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Date : 24 September 2016 — 2 January 2017</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Lutfi Ayu Art</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/07/07/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Lutfi Ayu Art" /><published>2017-07-07T17:23:08+07:00</published><updated>2017-07-07T17:23:08+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/07/07/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/07/07/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;This website created to show personal portofolio and disscusion about art. Authored by Lutfi ayu Wahyuni, Abstract Artist.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">This website created to show personal portofolio and disscusion about art. Authored by Lutfi ayu Wahyuni, Abstract Artist.</summary></entry></feed>
